Typhoon #13 is maintaining its extremely strong force
as it continues making its way north.
The storm area struck South Daitou Island last night at around 11 p.m.
As of now, the effect on transportation in all areas...
Daikichi!
The TV says the Shinkansen is pooping!
Not pooping! Operating!
Note: unko suru = pooping, unkou suru = in operation.
Pooping?
Operating!
They probably said, "The Shinkansen is operating on normal schedules."
That means it's running the same as usual.
The Shinkansen is pooping!
I'm going to go poop!
Jeez...
Typhoon #13 has changed course and is gradually moving east.
It is expected to make landfall in the Toukai area
sometime between this evening and night.
She said there's a typhoon!
It's all right. Typhoons come every year...
Daikichi!
Are you out of toilet paper?!
You should see how much I'm making!
Bring a ruler!
Boys are notoriously childish, but...
I can empathize.
ashita no koto wa wakannai
We don't know what'll happen tomorrow.
kore tte gisei to wa chigau
This feels different from a sacrifice.
nanika ga chigau
Something feels different.
batsu ge-mu ja nante omowanai
I'm not thinking of it as a punishment game.
de nande na no ka wa wakannai
I still don't know why.
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
Even though I don't quite feel satisfied with that,
kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nante mon ja nai
there's no question that you're important to me now.
owaranai koto nante kono yo no doko ni mo nai
There's nothing in this world that's endless.
naku no wa tsurain ja nai no
Isn't it painful having to cry?
ai no Sweet Drops, Sweet Drops
Love's sweet drops, sweet drops.
zutto yume mite itai ne
Don't you want to keep dreaming forever?
motto yasashiku shitai ne
Don't you want to be kinder?
kimi to iraretara Happy
As long as I'm with you, I'm happy.
onna no ko tte tsuyoi ne
Don't you think girls can be strong?
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne
Even though we can be weak sometimes.
bokura no negai wa Happy Happy Happy
Our wish is for happy, happy, happy.
sonna hibi mo Happy
Those days can also be happy.
Just wanna make you happy
Just wanna make you happy.
I'll pick you up early today.
Okay!
Kouki-kun, let's go!
Awesome, right?
We're going to be late.
See ya later!
If you leave just enough space for the circles,
it means you've written it in a cool way.
Got it?
Sensei, how much is "just enough"?
Um...
How many centimeters? How many millimeters?
You don't have to draw these circles!
Okay!
All right, the rest will be your homework.
For the next activity, all the first-graders are going to draw.
Meet up outside in front of your own morning glory.
Do you understand?
Yes!
Sandbags are that heavy?!
It's still morning, and I'm already beat...
And it had to be on a day like today when we've got tons of samples to ship...
Thank you.
What's that?
My kids' educational insurance...
Your kids are still babies!
If I waited until they got bigger, the insurance wouldn't mean a thing.
G-Good point.
We're enrolled too.
But since it's my kid, university might be impossible after all...
We have two, so it's pretty tough.
Ours is still really small, so we have ridiculous day care fees, you know.
His clothes become too small almost instantly...
Well, we're only contract employees, but...
it helps that the welfare pension program and health insurance are included.
How about life insurance?
My wife took care of that behind my back.
For mine, the payout is decent if I kick the bucket,
but she has universal life insurance.
The basic one...
You guys really are dads, aren't you?
I'm impressed.
There's nothing to be impressed about.
I wonder how much insurance costs...
The brat next door is so frickin' noisy, we wanna move,
but the money just ain't there.
Yeah, I don't even know what I'm working for...
Take a good look at us!
If you get married, this is what happens!
I don't have a girlfriend, so no danger of that.
They're always complaining, and yet...
Deep down, there's a sense of security.
I can't imagine them becoming like Rin's mother.
Kouki-san!
Sit down and draw!
Yikes!
What about your drawing board?
Eh... The ground is flat, so I don't need it.
That's no good!
When I tell you to bring something, you bring it!
Get it right now! Run!
Wow, your drawing is really good, Rin-chan!
Yeah, it is! That's great!
It's pretty!
I don't know...
That really is good!
The colors of this flower and this flower are slightly different,
and Rin-san's drawing shows that with both bluish and purplish colors.
You have a sharp eye.
Kouki-kun and those boys are wandering around again.
Kouki-san...
Right now, it's drawing time.
Kouki-san, your morning glories are looking splendid!
It would be a waste not to sketch them.
Kouki-san, do you like drawing?
It's okay, I guess...
Tatsumi-sensei...
I'm in charge of this boy.
Kouki-san, why do you always, always disturb everyone?!
Now sit down and draw!
And don't make a weird face!
I got Kouki's hat!
Cut it out!
Hey! Kouki-san! Boys!
Stop fooling around!
Get back here!
I got it! I got it!
Rin-chan?
Kouki-kun!
Sit down and draw!
Don't let them get you in trouble!
Okay.
That was incredible, Rin-chan.
Kouki-kun always does strange stuff, and he's scary when he loses his temper.
Rin-chan, he'll bully you!
No, he won't! After all, we went to the same nursery school.
Really?
They're late...
You guys pick up your kids at 6 too, right?
Yeah. Cutting it close today.
Here they are!
All right! Let's get it done in one!
Yeah!
Hello!
You got a little wet, huh?
Rin-chan! Your father's here!
Hey...
I-I'm sorry...
Not at all. Don't worry about it.
I'll go get Rin-chan.
The wind's really picked up, huh?
Yes. I wish I could've gotten here earlier, but...
Am I the last?
Kouki-kun is here, too...
Daikichi!
There's a storm, huh?
Yeah. It's really coming down.
Sorry I'm late.
It's okay.
An umbrella's flying!
Did something happen?
Uh-uh. I'm fine.
See ya!
See you later, Kouki!
Want to walk home together?
Let's walk home together!
Sure!
I'm sorry. Since it's already been decided, something like that is...
I know. But the wind is only going to keep getting stronger,
so let me try calling Nitani-san to see if it would be a problem.
Then, just to confirm, can I hand the phone over to you?
Um, in that case...
We can go home early too!
What's that?!
Well, we were just kidding.
Kouki!
Me too!
Rin!
That's dangerous!
Get behind me and follow along!
Hold it!
I'll bring you a towel.
The storm windows!
Cool! Let me do it!
Careful. Don't pinch your fingers.
It's dark!
You know, it's kind of like a secret base!
It's in my eyes!
I'm going to rinse it off now, so don't open your eyes.
All right, dry the rest yourself.
Daikichi, your back is huge!
I know, right?
Good evening! It's Nitani!
Yes! I'll be right there!
So you were able to get off work early...
I feel like I overstepped my bounds.
Not at all! It was a big help.
Sorry. Kouki got soaked on the way here, too.
Really, for anything and everything, I'm sorry...
That looks good on you!
Daikichi, let me borrow yours!
That again?! It's "Daikichi-san," right?
He said "Daikichi" is fine!
Yeah, I'm more comfortable with that.
That's right!
Calling Daikichi "Daikichi" is fine!
Rin-chan, you're good at that!
I can use a knife, too!
You're already a young lady!
Daikichi does the fire, though.
I'll do it too!
You never help out...
I'll cut too!
I'll lend you my knife!
Oh, no! Onions are dangerous!
Don't touch! Wash your eyes right away!
Where are you going?
Oh, no! I'm crying!
You're making hamburger patties...
Yep.
It looks delicious, doesn't it?
These are kind of strange...
They're not strange! Right?
Well, I'm sure they'll taste fine.
Rin-chan! The eggs are boiled!
Please peel them!
Okay!
Here!
You're so good at that!
That Rin is in such high spirits...
Kouki, do you love your mom?
If only she weren't such an old nag...
There's a sense of security here, too.
This one's mine!
What about giving thanks?
Thank you for the food!
Kouki, use your chopsticks!
I know, I'm just getting it together.
It's good, isn't it?!
It really is!
Food tastes better when we eat it together!
Let's eat here again tomorrow night!
Kouki!
That's good enough.
I'll finish up later.
Okay.
And then it hit him right on the head!
He's so excited...
I was never able to give him this kind of opportunity until now.
I'm so happy about this evening.
Thank you.
Oh, I didn't... I need to thank you!
Sensei said we didn't need those circles!
Being able to see that face...
I'm glad I got off work early.
She's raising a child alone, too...
Daikichi! Come here a second!
All right...
Well, I think it's about time...
Shall I call a taxi?
Yes, thank you.
Why don't you stay over?
Rin!
After all, Reina-chan and her mom stayed over.
That was different!
See ya tomorrow...
See you!
Bye-bye!
Rin-chan, thank you.
Thank you very much.
We had fun, too.
Right?
Uh-huh!
Bye-bye!
nichiyou no hareta hirusagari
It's a sunny Sunday, early in the afternoon.
kyou wa doko e yukou?
Where should we go today?
kayoi nareta itsumo no michi ga
This path I've grown so used to taking
mabushiku kagayaite mieru
seems to be shining brightly,
terasu atatakai taiyou to
as long as the warm sun is shining
tonari ni kimi ga ireba
and you are here beside me.
mou High High High
I'm already high, high, high.
hashagidasu kimochi ni
I feel like frolicking about.
utae Life Life Life
Let's sing, life, life, life.
koe wa dokomademo
Our voices can go anywhere.
mou High High High
I'm already high, high, high.
maiagaru kaze ni nori
I'm riding on the rising wind.
utae Life Life Life
Let's sing, life, life, life.
koe mo tobihaneru
Even our voices will be bouncing.
The typhoon left, huh?
Yep.
Rin-chan! Rin-chan!
Kouki-kun is here already!
He's early again!
Come on in!
Are you sure?
Hold on!
Wait!
I wanted to open the storm windows...
Not a cloud in the sky!
See you later!
Kouki-kun, we're going to be late!
See ya later!
Everybody, cooking in 30 seconds!
Kouki's mom made me a perfect gruel for a cold!
You start with konbu soup, than you put in carrots, mushrooms, pumpkin, and onion.
Then you cut in small pieces of potato and boil it gently.
Then you take it from the fire and season it with salt and soy sauce.
Last you put in the rice.
Episode 10
Stomach Flu
The next story is "Stomach Flu."
Please eat.